RG 016, Department of Public Health
Connecticut State Library
Department of Public Health records
1799-2014
bulk, 1877-2014
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Dept. of Public Health
951 cubic feet
The Department of Public Health is the State's lead agency in public health policy and advocacy.
RG016
Historical Note
The Connecticut State Board of Health, now called the Department of Public Health, was established in 1878. The original legislation designated a membership of six persons including at least three physicians. The Governor was to appoint the members with the advice and consent of the Senate. The six members then elected a Secretary who received a salary of one thousand dollars per annum.
The General Assembly mandated the Board of Health to "take cognizance of the interests of health and life" of the people of the State. It was to make sanitary investigations, inquiries into the causes of disease and sources of mortality, to collect information about these matters, and issue appropriate reports. The General Assembly also empowered it to distribute sanitary information to local health authorities upon their request and likewise to gather information relative to sanitary conditions, health, and disease from local officials. The new State Board of Health was also given general supervision of birth, marriage, and death registrations.
Over the years, the department’s mandate has been very fluid. In 1919 the Board of Health was reorganized into the Department of Health. In 1979 it was reorganized again into the Department of Health Services. In 1993 it merged with the Connecticut Alcohol and Drug Abuse Commission into the Department of Public Health and Addiction Services. In 1995 it became the Department of Public Health when programs dealing with substance abuse and addition were transferred to the new Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services.
See also the.
Scope and Content
Early records are primarily correspondence and local surveys for Dr. Charles W. Chamberlain, the first Secretary of the State Board of Health. Chamberlain, was born in Providence, Rhode Island, on July 21, 1844. He graduated from Brown University in 1867 and the College of Physicians and Surgeons of New York City in 1871. He settled in Hartford and quickly became an authority on public hygiene and sanitation questions. He probably had the most responsibility for the establishment of the State Board of Health. He served as its first Secretary from 1876 to 1833. He also served as Secretary of the Connecticut Medical Society. He died on August 21, 1884.
Most of the early correspondence concerns routine matters. Some local correspondence, however, when used with material derived from two town surveys, is useful to researchers interested in community or state health conditions. The most controversial early issue involving the State Board of Health came after the legislature passed an act in 1880 requiring eye examinations for railroad employees. Correspondence directed to the Secretary concerning the implementation of the law, together with 133 petitions protesting against its harshness, provide an excellent example of the work of the Board of Health in its efforts to promote health and safety. Further material in the record group includes divorce statistics from 1878 to 1883, occupational breakdowns for employment in four counties, copies of legislation and petitions, vital statistics forms, copies of circulars, and copies of speeches written by Dr. Chamberlain.
More recent records cover the broad spectrum of programs administered by the department including the Nation’s most comprehensive tumor registry and the licensure of health professionals and institutional programs in the state.
Arrangement
Series 1-13. Early records, Accession: T000516 and T000508, 7.25 cubic feet
Includes Connecticut and general correspondence, town surveys, rail road worker eye tests, malaria survey, divorces, occupational survey, plans and maps, legislation and petitions, vital statistics forms, circulars, speeches, and miscellaneous papers.
Series 14. Connecticut State Planning Committee for Mid-century White House Conference on Children and Youth, Accession: T000516, 2 cubic feet
Series 15. Governor's Conference on Children and Youth, Accession: T000516, 4 cubic feet
Series 16. Connecticut Advisory School Health Council, 1954-1971, Accession: 1989-012, 2.25 cubic feet
Series 17. Medical Registration Applications, 1893-1976, 86 cubic feet
Accession: T000512, Doctors' licensure files, 1893-1940.
Accession: 1989-013, Doctors' licensure files, 1941-1976
Accession: 1996-017, Applications for Healing Arts certificates, 1925-1975, LPN licensure files, 1935-1941, RN by exam licensure files, 1905-1941, RN ENDO/Reciprocity licensure files, 1915-1941
Series 18. Not in use
Series 19. New Haven County. Census Statistics, 1884-1897, Accession: T000501, 1 volume (.25 cubic feet)
Series 20. State Board of Health, 1878-1917, 1 cubic foot
Includes meeting minutes and reports.
Accession: T000507, .25 cubic feet
Accession: 1987-030A, .75 cubic feet
Series 21. Tuberculosis Commission / Tuberculosis Control, Hospital Care and Rehabilitation Division., 1909-1988, 3.25 cubic feet
Accession: 1985-029, Minutes, administrative files, photographs, scrapbooks, 1909-1975, 2.5 cubic feet.
Accession: 1989-051, Photographs, 1979-1988, .25 cubic feet
Accession: 1998-017, Photographs, 1957-1958, .25 cubic feet
Accession: T003188, School vaccine plan, circa 1937, .25 cubic feet
Series 22-23. Not used.
Series 24. Hospital and Medical Care Division, 1966-1981, 16.25 cubic feet
Accession: 1985-026C, Institutional licensure files, 1977, 5.5 cubic feet
Accession: 1986-010A, Institutional licensure files, 1978, 5.5 cubic feet
Accession: 1989-035, Institutional licensure files, 1981, 5 cubic feet
Accession: 2013-042, Agricultural Workers Hospital file, 1966-1975, .25 cubic feet
Series 25. Dr. Stanley H. Osborne collection, 1799-1979, 12.5 cubic feet
Accession: T000520, Collection, 1799-1979, 3.5 cubic feet
Accession: 1986-038, Scrapbooks, 1918-1972, 9 cubic feet
Series 26. Commission on Hospitals and Health Care, 1974-1987, Accession1991-002, 20 cubic feet
Series 27. Commissioner, 1944-1945, 1973, .75 cubic feet
Accession: T000510, Annual report, 1944-1945, .5 cubic feet
Accession: 1995-045, Manual, 1973, .25 cubic feet
Series 28. Community Nursing and Home Health Division, 1918-1980, Accession: 1988-028, 2 cubic feet
Series 29. Commission on Long Term Care, 1980-1990, 18 cubic feet
Accession: 1992-002, Coordinator's Records, 1980-1990, 16 cubic feet
Accession: 1996-031, Administrative Records, 1986-1987, 2 cubic feet
Series 30. Local Health Administration, 1931-1981, 12.5 cubic feet
Accession: T000503, Circulars, 1937-1972, 1 cubic foot
Accession: 1996-011, Annual Reports of Town Health Officials, 1931-1981, 11.5 cubic feet
Series 31. Not in use.
Series 32. Tumor Registry Division. Case files, 741 cubic feet.
Accession: 1992-052, 91 cubic feet
Accession: 1993-130, 201 cubic feet
Accession: 1995-073, 99 cubic feet
Accession: 1995-074, 350 cubic feet
Series 33. Public Health Office Maternal and Child Health Program, 1955-1984, Accession: 1995-002, 1 cubic foot
Series 34. Bureau of Laboratories / Laboratory Division, 1943-1976, 2.25 cubic feet
Accession: 1994-009A, Annual reports, 1943-1956, 2 cubic feet
Accession: T003189, Proposal for building addition, 1976, .25 cubic feet
Series 35. Hearing Office, 1893-2014
Accession 1994-020, 2 cubic feet
Includes minutes for the Board of Examiners for Nursing, 1905-1992.
See also accessions 2008-039 and 2011-131.
Accession: 2000-004, 1893-1991, 8 cubic feet
Includes minutes for the following boards: Connecticut Medical Examining Board, 1940-1975; Healing Arts, 1944-1975; Connecticut State Dental Commission, 1965-1991; Connecticut Homeopathic Medical Examining Board, 1978-1989; Connecticut Board of Examiners for Opticians, 1935-1983; Connecticut State Dental Commission, 1893-1975; Connecticut State Board of Examiners for Physical Therapists, 1941-1979; Connecticut Board of Examiners for Optometrists, 1932-1979; Connecticut Board of Veterinary Medicine, 1960-1981; Connecticut Board of Examiners of Embalmers & Funeral Directors, 1963-1982; Connecticut Osteopathic Examining Board, 1911-1967; Connecticut State Barber Board, 1949-1980; Connecticut Board of Examiners of Hypertrichologists, 1976-1981; Connecticut Board of Audiologists and Speech Pathologists, 1973-1979; Connecticut State Board of Nursing Home Administrators, 1974-1979; Connecticut State Board of Chiropractic Examiners, 1928-1972; Connecticut Board of Examiners of Podiatry, 1930-1979; Connecticut Medical Examining Board, 1894-1987.
Accession 2008-039, 2 cubic feet
Includes minutes for the Board of Examiners for Nursing, 1993-2007.
See also accessions 1994-020 and 2011-131.
Accession 2011-131, .25 cubic feet
Includes minutes for the Board of Examiners for Nursing, 2008-2012.
See also accessions 1994-020 and 2008-039.
Accession 2014-032, .25 cubic feet
Includes minutes for the Connecticut Stem Cell Research Advisory Committee, 2005-2012.
Series 36. Commission on the Care and Treatment of the Chronically Ill, Aged and Infirm, 1946, Accession: 2002-018, 1 folder
Series 37. Division of Health Systems Regulation, 1948-1976, Accession: 2004-005, 3.5 cubic feet
Series 38. Photographs, 1977-1980, Accession: 1994-009, 3 cubic feet
Series 39. Printed Material, 1941-1988, .5 cubic feet
Accessions: 1995-072, 1999-136, 2002-079
Series 40. Bureau of Administrative and Support Services, 1996-2001, 1 cubic foot
Accession: 2013-021 Project files for Quality of Work Life project and Toxicology Laboratory transfer to Dept. of Public Safety.
Related Material
RG 179, State Special Care Sanatorium
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Dept. of Public Health; Connecticut State Tuberculosis Commission
Persons:
Chamberlain, Charles W.; Osborne, Stanley H.
Subjects:
Connecticut. Dept. of Public Health -- Records and correspondence; Connecticut State Tuberculosis Commission -- Records and correspondence; Public health -- Connecticut; Hispanic Americans -- Medical care; Tobacco workers -- Connecticut; Puerto Ricans -- Medical care
Document Types:
Application forms; Case files; Circulars (fliers); Correspondence; Minutes; Petitions; Photographs; Questionnaires; Reports; Scrapbooks; Speeches; Surveys (documents)
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Series 1. Connecticut Correspondence, 1878-1884; T000516; 5.5 inches
  Much of the correspondence directed to the Secretary of the Board of Health is routine concerning suggestions, requests for additional vital statistics forms, and for the Board's publications. There are occasionally valuable letters concerning community health problems. Box 1 also contains an itemized list for boxes 1-6.
  Arranged alphabetically by town and village and then chronologically. Undated material is at the end. Villages like Riverton and Sandy Hook, which are parts of Barkhamsted and Newton, are under R and S respectively, the initial letter of the village. Researchers should check both villages and towns to gather all pertinent information.
  - A-V (Box 1)
  - W-Z (Box 2)
- Series 2. General Correspondence, 1877-1892; T000516; 4.5 inches
  - Records (Box 2)
    Mostly routine correspondence from all over the United States and some foreign countries asking for or acknowledging receipt of publications. Only a small proportion relates to matters concerning the Board of Health.
    Arranged chronologically. Bulk of material covers 1878-1884.
- Series 3. Town Surveys, 1878; T000516; 1 inch
  - Records (Box 3)
    Surveys of thirty-five towns and villages. Some information about topography and crops grown in the community. The main focus, however, is on possible health hazards and completeness of vital statistic registration.
    Arranged alphabetically by towns and villages.
- Series 4. Rail Road Worker Eye Tests, 1880; T000516; 8 inches
  - Records (Box 3-4)
    In 1880, the General Assembly passed an act requiring all railroad employees to be examined for "color-blindness and visual power. (See series 9.)
    Correspondence comes from railroad executives, employees, and physicians giving examinations. Also included are twelve certificates of examination ad 133 petitions from railroad employees and citizens throughout the state complaining that the rules are too severe. They request that the legislature modify the examinations. The petitions often list signer's address and occupation. Note: No petition between numbers 177 and 199 discovered.
    Correspondence arranged chronologically and certificates and petitions arranged numerically.
- Series 5. Malaria Survey, 1881; T000516; 2 inches
  Survey of more than 120 towns and villages in Connecticut to determine the incidence of malaria.
  Arranged alphabetically by town and village.
  - A-O (Box 4)
  - P-W (Box 5)
- Series 6. Divorce Returns, 1878-1883; 2.25 cubic feet
  - 1878-1883, T000516; 1 inch (Box 5)
    Statistics from the eight county Superior Courts on divorces granted. Causes for divorce and some names of the parties given.
    Arranged chronologically and alphabetically by county.
  - 1880-1881, T000508; 2.25 cubic feet (Box Item 13)
    Statistics from Hartford (1880), New London (1881), and Windham (1880) Superior Courts on divorces granted. Causes for divorce and some names of the parties given.
    Oversize flat box.
- Series 7. Occupational Survey, undated; T000516; .25 inches
  - Records (Box 5)
    Statistical data on employment by occupation in Fairfield, Litchfield, New London, and Tolland counties. Possibly taken from the 1880 census.
    Statistics divided into ten year age groups.
- Series 8. Plans and Maps, undated; T000516; .25 inches
  - Records (Box 5)
    Bridgeport Hospital, proposed sewage system in Waterbury, boy's closets, and a home heating system.
- Series 9. Legislation and Petitions, undated; T000516; 1 inch
  - Records (Box 5)
    Includes copy of the act establishing the Board of Health, and copies of eight other acts, resolutions, and petitions including the legislation requiring eye exams for railroad employees. Also numerous copies of unsigned petitions concerning physician registration.
    Unarranged.
- Series 10. Vital Statistics Forms, undated; T000516; 1.5 inches
  - Records (Box 5)
    Connecticut forms separated from other states.
- Series 11. Circulars, undated; T000516; 2 inches
  - Records (Box 6)
    Numerous copies of Circular No. 2 stating the purpose of the Connecticut State Board of Health. It asked for correspondents in each town and village. Also includes other states circulars and publications, a circular from the National Board of Health, and material from the American Public Health Association.
    Circulars from other states are arranged alphabetically by state.
- Series 12. Speeches, undated; T000516; 2 inches
  - Speeches (Box 6)
    Most handwritten by Dr. Chamberlain.
- Series 13. Miscellaneous papers, undated; T000516; 1 inch
  - Records (Box 6)
- Series 14. Connecticut State Planning Committee for Mid-Century White House Conference on Children and Youth, 1948-1952; T000516; 2 cubic feet
  - Records (Box 7-8)
    Minutes, correspondence, working papers.
- Series 15. Governor's Committee and Children and Youth, 1952-1953; T000516; 4 cubic feet
  - Records (Box 9-12)
    Minutes, correspondence, working papers, publications and reports.
- Series 16. Connecticut Advisory School Health Council, 1954-1971; 1989-012; 2.25 cubic feet
  - Records, 1954-1971 (Box 1-3)
    Minutes and files.
    Unprocessed.
- Series 17. Medical Registration Applications, 1893-1976; 86 cubic feet
  Legislation passed in 1893 required formal registration prior to practicing medicine, surgery, or midwifery. Before 1893 private state medical societies issued licenses. Until 1976, the Licensure and Registration section handled registrations. PA 77-164 created the Examination Section to assume these duties. In 1978, the Division of Medical Quality Assurance absorbed both sections.
  Application books contain information regarding an applicant's education, hospitals practiced at, area of specialization and after 1924, a photograph.
  Arranged chronologically by year and therein alphabetically by surname.
  See also RG 138, Connecticut Medical Society, 1712-1912.
  - 1893-1940, T000512; 31 volumes
    - A-B, 1893-1907 (Box Volume 1)
    - C-D, 1893-1907 (Box Volume 2)
    - E-G, 1893-1907 (Box Volume 3)
    - H-I, 1893-1907 (Box Volume 4)
    - J-L, 1893-1907 (Box Volume 5)
    - M-O, 1893-1907 (Box Volume 6)
    - N-R, 1893-1907 (Box Volume 7)
    - S, 1893-1907 (Box Volume 8)
    - T-Z, 1893-1907 (Box Volume 9)
    - A-K, 1908-1917 (Box Volume 10)
    - L-Z, 1908-1917 (Box Volume 11)
    - 1918-1919 (Box Volume 12)
    - 1920-1921 (Box Volume 13)
    - 1922-1923 (Box Volume 14)
    - 1924 (Box Volume 15)
    - 1925 (Box Volume 16)
    - 1926 (Box Volume 17)
    - 1927 (Box Volume 18)
    - 1928 (Box Volume 19)
    - 1929 (Box Volume 20)
    - 1930 (Box Volume 21)
    - 1931 (Box Volume 22)
    - 1932 (Box Volume 23)
    - 1933 (Box Volume 24)
    - 1934 (Box Volume 25)
    - 1935 (Box Volume 26)
    - 1936 (Box Volume 27)
    - 1937 (Box Volume 28)
    - 1938 (Box Volume 29)
    - 1939 (Box Volume 30)
    - 1940 (Box Volume 31)
  - Medical Quality Assurance, 1941-1976
    - Doctors licensure files, 1941-1976; 1989-013
      - 1941, 1 volume (Box 1)
      - 1942, 1 volume (Box 1)
      - 1943, 1 volume (Box 1)
      - 1944, 1 volume (Box 1)
      - 1945, 1 volume (Box 2)
      - A-K, 1946; 1 volume (Box 2)
      - K-Z, 1946; 1 volume (Box 2)
      - A-K, 1947; 1 volume (Box 2)
      - K-Z, 1947; 1 volume (Box 3)
      - A-J, 1948; 1 volume (Box 3)
      - J-Z, 1948; 1 volume (Box 3)
      - A-K, 1949; 1 volume (Box 3)
      - L-Z, 1949; 1 volume (Box 3)
      - A-J, 1950; 1 volume (Box 4)
      - K-Z, 1950; 1 volume (Box 4)
      - A-K, 1951; 1 volume (Box 4)
      - L-Z, 1951; 1 volume (Box 4)
      - A-K, 1952; 1 volume (Box 4)
      - L-Z, 1952; 1 volume (Box 5)
      - A-K, 1953; 1 volume (Box 5)
      - L-Z, 1953; 1 volume (Box 5)
      - A-F, 1954; 1 volume (Box 5)
      - G-M, 1954; 1 volume (Box 5)
      - N-Z, 1954; 1 volume (Box 6)
      - A-G, 1955; 1 volume (Box 6)
      - H-N, 1955; 1 volume (Box 6)
      - O-Z, 1955; 1 volume (Box 6)
      - A-G, 1956; 1 volume (Box 6)
      - H-P, 1956; 1 volume (Box 6)
      - Q-Z, 1956; 1 volume (Box 6)
      - A-G, 1957; 1 volume (Box 7)
      - H-O, 1957; 1 volume (Box 7)
      - P-Z, 1957; 1 volume (Box 7)
      - A-F, 1958; 1 volume (Box 7)
      - G-O, 1958; 1 volume (Box 7)
      - P-Z, 1958; 1 volume (Box 7)
      - A-F, 1959; 1 volume (Box 8)
      - G-N, 1959; 1 volume (Box 8)
      - O-Z, 1959; 1 volume (Box 8)
      - A-G, 1960; 1 volume (Box 8)
      - H-M, 1960; 1 volume (Box 8)
      - N-Z, 1960; 1 volume (Box 8)
      - A-F, 1961; 1 volume (Box 9)
      - G-N, 1961; 1 volume (Box 9)
      - O-Z, 1961; 1 volume (Box 9)
      - A-G, 1962; 1 volume (Box 9)
      - H-N, 1962; 1 volume (Box 9)
      - O-Z, 1962; 1 volume (Box 9)
      - A-G, 1963; 1 volume (Box 10)
      - H-O, 1963; 1 volume (Box 10)
      - P-Z, 1963; 1 volume (Box 10)
      - A-F, 1964; 1 volume (Box 10)
      - G-N, 1964; 1 volume (Box 10)
      - O-Z, 1964; 1 volume (Box 10)
      - A-F, 1965; 1 volume (Box 11)
      - G-M, 1965; 1 volume (Box 11)
      - N-Z, 1965; 1 volume (Box 11)
      - A-G, 1966; 1 volume (Box 12)
      - H-O, 1966; 1 volume (Box 12)
      - P-Z, 1966; 1 volume (Box 12)
      - A-F, 1967; 1 volume (Box 12)
      - G-M, 1967; 1 volume (Box 12)
      - N-Z, 1967; 1 volume (Box 12)
      - A-G, 1968; 1 volume (Box 13)
      - H-M, 1968; 1 volume (Box 13)
      - N-Z, 1968; 1 volume (Box 13)
      - A-F, 1969; 1 volume (Box 13)
      - G-M, 1969; 1 volume (Box 13)
      - N-Z, 1969; 1 volume (Box 14)
      - A-F, 1970; 1 volume (Box 14)
      - G-O, 1970; 1 volume (Box 14)
      - P-Z, 1970; 1 volume (Box 14)
      - A-E, 1971; 1 volume (Box 15)
      - F-K, 1971; 1 volume (Box 15)
      - L-R, 1971; 1 volume (Box 15)
      - S-Z, 1971; 1 volume (Box 15)
      - A-F, 1972; 1 volume (Box 15)
      - G-M, 1972; 1 volume (Box 16)
      - N-Z, 1972; 1 volume (Box 16)
      - A-C, 1973; 1 volume (Box 16)
      - D-I, 1973; 1 volume (Box 16)
      - J-M, 1973; 1 volume (Box 16)
      - N-R, 1973; 1 volume (Box 17)
      - S-Z, 1973; 1 volume (Box 17)
      - A-C, 1974; 1 volume (Box 17)
      - D-G, 1974; 1 volume (Box 17)
      - H-L, 1974; 1 volume (Box 17)
      - M-R, 1974; 1 volume (Box 17)
      - S-Z, 1974; 1 volume (Box 18)
      - A-C, 1975; 1 volume (Box 18)
      - D-G, 1975; 1 volume (Box 18)
      - H-L, 1975; 1 volume (Box 18)
      - M-P, 1975; 1 volume (Box 18)
      - Q-S, 1975; 1 volume (Box 19)
      - T-Z, 1975; 1 volume (Box 19)
      - A-C, 1976; 1 volume (Box 19)
      - D-G, 1976; 1 volume (Box 19)
      - H-K, 1976; 1 volume (Box 19)
      - L-N, 1976; 1 volume (Box 20)
      - O-R, 1976; 1 volume (Box 20)
      - S, 1976; 1 volume (Box 20)
      - T-Z, 1976; 1 volume (Box 20)
    - Applications for Healing Arts certificates, 1925-1975; 1996-017
      - 1-239, 1925-1928 (Box 1)
      - 240-559, 1928-1932 (Box 2)
      - 560-845, 1932-1934 (Box 3)
      - 846-1238, 1934-1937 (Box 4)
      - 1239-1572, 1937-1940 (Box 5)
      - 1573-1899, 1940-1942 (Folder 6)
      - 1900-2250, 1942-1946 (Box 7)
      - 2251-2599, 1946-1948 (Box 8)
      - 2600-2899, 1948-1950 (Box 9)
      - 2900-3160, 1950-1952 (Box 10)
      - 3161-3459, 1952-1954 (Box 11)
      - 3460-3730, 1954-1955 (Box 12)
      - 3731-3999, 1955-1957 (Box 13)
      - 4000-4249, 1957-1958 (Box 14)
      - 4250-4474, 1958 (Box 15)
      - 4474-4704, 1958-1959 (Box 16)
      - 4705-4952, 1959-1960 (Box 17)
      - 4953-5194, 1960 (Box 18)
      - 5195-5414, 1960-1961 (Box 19)
      - 5415-5662, 1961-1962 (Box 20)
      - 5663-5899, 1962-1963 (Box 21)
      - 5900-6140, 1963-1964 (Box 22)
      - 6141-6409, 1964-1965 (Box 23)
      - 6411-6689, 1965-1966 (Box 24)
      - 6690-6897, 1966-1967 (Box 25)
      - 6898-7150, 1967-1968 (Box 26)
      - 7151-7422, 1968-1969 (Box 27)
      - 7423-7676, 1969-1970 (Box 28)
      - 7677-7929, 1970-1971 (Box 29)
      - 7930-8054, 1971 (Box 30)
      - 8055-8296, 1971-1973 (Box 31)
      - 8297-8561, 1973 (Box 32)
      - 8562-8859, 1973-1974 (Box 33)
      - 8860-9155, 1974-1975 (Box 34)
    - LPN licensure files, 1935-1941; 1996-017
      - 1-1100, 1936 February 15-July 15 (Box 1)
      - 1101-2000, 1936 July 15-1940 January 23 (Box 2)
      - 2001-2600, 1940 January 23-August 1 (Box 3)
      - 2681-1980, 1940 August 1-1941 February 3 (Box 4)
    - RN by exam licensure files, 1905-1941; 1996-017
      - 1-900, 1905 October 20-1914 February 28 (Box 1)
      - 951-1800, 1914 February 28-1918 June 20 (Box 2)
      - 1801-2700, 1918 July 6-1921 June 16 (Box 3)
      - 2701-3580, 1921 June 16-1925 June 17 (Box 4)
      - 3581-4450, 1924 June 19-1926 October 31 (Box 5)
      - 4451-5350, 1926 July 31-1928 September 1 (Box 6)
      - 5351-6200, 1928 June 30-1929 November 14 (Box 7)
      - 6201-7030, 1929 December 21-1931 February 14 (Box 8)
      - 7031-7800, 1931 January 26-1932 November 2 (Box 9)
      - 7801-8540, 1932 October 22-1934 January 8 (Box 10)
      - 8541-9250, 1934 June 23-1935 October 19 (Box 11)
      - 9251-9980, 1935 November 22-1937 June 17 (Box 12)
      - 9981-10580, 1937 August 19-1938 October 14 (Box 13)
      - 10581-11130, 1938 October 14-1939 November 28 (Box 14)
      - 11131-11470, 1939 November 28-1940 December 13 (Box 15)
      - 11471-11720, 1940 December 13-1941 January 10 (Box 16)
    - RN ENDO/Reciprocity licensure files, 1915-1941; 1996-017
      - 1-720, 1915 January 3-1930 January 14 (Box 1)